Guide to the James Gamble Rogers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1890s-1984; Accession 1988-M-016; 31.75 linear feet (41 boxes)
  - Drawings, photographs, and construction notes
    - Other buildings
      - Upright
        - Christ Church, Rye (N.Y.), [undated] (Box 27, Folder 145)
        - Colgate Rochester Divinity School, Rochester (N.Y.), 1931 (Box 27, Folder 146a-b)
        - Crane Company exhibit buildings, Atlantic City (N.J.), 1924-1925 (Box 27, Folder 147a-b)
        - Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York City, 1948-1950 (Box 27, Folder 148)
        - Mystic Chapel, Mystic (Conn.), [undated] (Box 27, Folder 149)
        - New Haven (Conn.) Post Office and Court House, [ca. 1914-1918] (Box 27, Folder 150-151)
        - New Haven (Conn.) Post Office and Court House, [ca. 1911-1916] (Box 28, Folder 152-157)
        - New Haven (Conn.) Post Office and Court House, [ca. 1916-1918] (Box 29, Folder 158-159)
        - New York City: medical center, [ca. 1927-1928] (Box 29, Folder 160-161)
          See also: box 23, folder 106
        - Unidentified, [undated] (Box 29, Folder 162)
  - Published material
    - Aetna Life Insurance Co., 1923-1931 (Box 30, Folder 163)
    - Branford College (Memorial Quadrangle), [1918-1926] (Box 30, Folder 164-167)
    - Columbia University Library, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 168)
    - Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 169)
    - New York City: medical center, 1924-1933 (Box 31, Folder 170)
    - Northwestern University, 1925-1928 (Box 31, Folder 171)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, 1919-1932 (Box 31, Folder 172)
    - Western College, Oxford (Ohio), [ca. 1939] (Box 31, Folder 173)
    - Yale-in-China, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 174)
  - Legal and financial records
    - Contract files
      - Aetna Life Insurance, 1922-1929 (Box 32, Folder 175-176)
      - Atlanta University, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 177)
      - Brooks Memorial Tennessee; Central Bank and Trust, 1909-1916 (Box 32, Folder 178)
      - Clark College, 1939-1940 (Box 32, Folder 179)
      - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, 1930-1939 (Box 32, Folder 180)
      - Columbia Presbyterian Hospital and College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1923-1937 (Box 32, Folder 181)
      - Columbia University Library, 1930-1935 (Box 32, Folder 182)
      - Concordia Lutheran Collegiate Institute Gymnasium, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 183)
      - Connecticut College Chapel, 1938-1939 (Box 32, Folder 184)
      - Connecticut General Life Insurance Company, 1918-1919, 1936-1937 (Box 32, Folder 185)
      - Creek, Inc.; Queen City Club, 1922, 1927-1928 (Box 32, Folder 186)
      - Engineering Building of United Engineering Society, 1906 (Box 32, Folder 187)
      - Exhibit Building, Atlantic City, (N.J.), 1924 (Box 32, Folder 188)
      - Featherbed Lane Presbyterian Church, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 189)
      - Harkness, E.S., 1907-1909, 1925-1927 (Box 32, Folder 190-191)
      - Hospitals and health centers, 1936-1949 (Box 32, Folder 192-194)
      - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1916, 1923 (Box 32, Folder 195)
      - Marine Historical Association, Inc., Mystic (Conn.), 1939-1942 (Box 32, Folder 196)
      - Miriam Osborn Memorial House, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 197)
      - Neurological Institute of New York, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 198)
      - New Haven (Conn.) Post Office, [1908-1917] (Box 33, Folder 199)
      - New Orleans (La.) Post Office, 1908-1913, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 200)
      - New York City Medical Center (Memorial Hospital), 1921-1939 (Box 33, Folder 201)
      - New York World's Fair, Inc., 1937 (Box 33, Folder 202)
      - Northwestern University, 1923-1941 (Box 33, Folder 203-205)
      - Residences, 1905-1931 (Box 33, Folder 206-207)
      - Schools, 1908 (Box 34, Folder 208)
      - Schools, 1908-1937 (Box 34, Folder 209)
      - Shelby County Courthouse, 1905-1908 (Box 34, Folder 210)
      - Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1922-1924 (Box 34, Folder 211)
      - Yale University
        - Branford College (Memorial Quadrangle), 1917-1919 (Box 34, Folder 212)
        - Other, 1923-1935 (Box 34, Folder 213)
      - Yale-in-China, 1914 (Box 34, Folder 214)
      - Yale Club, New York City, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 215)
      - Yeoman's Hall Co. small cottages, 1927-1939 (Box 34, Folder 216)
      - Miscellaneous, 1905-1949 (Box 34, Folder 217)
    - Hale and Rogers
      - Checkbooks, 1905-1906 (Box 35, Folder 218-219)
      - Daybook, 1905-1912 (Box 35, Folder 220)
      - Payrolls, 1905-1913 (Box 35, Folder 221-222)
      - Profit and loss statement, 1908 (Box 35, Folder 223)
    - James Gamble Rogers, Inc.
      - Minutebook, 1923-1946 (Box 36, Folder 224a-c)
      - Commissions notebook, 1932 (Box 37, Folder 225)
      - Payroll, 1924-1926 (Box 37, Folder 226)
      - Planning notebook, [ca. 1920s] (Box 37, Folder 227)
  - Personal papers
    - James Gamble Rogers
      - Correspondence, 1921, 1931-1932, 1940 (Box 38, Folder 228)
      - Fred Sutton's book on stone, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 229)
      - Memorabilia, 1918-1934 (Box 38, Folder 230)
        See also: box 41, folder 237
      - Photographs, personal, [undated] (Box 38, Folder 231)
      - Printed material, 1906, 1938 (Box 38, Folder 232)
      - Speech and writings notes, [1930s] (Box 38, Folder 233)
    - Francis Day Rogers
      - Alumni Association of St. Paul's, 1942-1949 (Box 39, Folder 234)
      - Federation of East Lyme Beaches, 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 235)
      - R&B Son: Staff-Office News, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 236)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 39, Folder 237)
  - Oversize
    - Architectural reference files, [ca. 1905-1912] (Box 40)
    - "Some of the Larger and Most Recent Work of Jas. Gamble Rogers, Inc. Architects" New York City, 1941 (Box 41)
    - Drawings and photographs, 1916, 1925, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Rogers' Diplome D'Architecte, Ecole Nationale et Speciale des Beaux-Arts, Paris, 1899 February 4 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Proposal for Rutgers University Library, Undated (Folder 42A)
- Additional Material, 1915-1917; Accession 1989-M-045; 1
  Addition Inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1989 January
  Received from the Department of Architectural and Engineering Services, 1988 October 26
  - New Haven (Conn.) Post Office and Court House: 13 blueprints of elevations, plans, and sections, 1915-1917 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1937, 1946, 1972; Accession 1995-M-010; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1994 Aug
  Received from: Pauline W. Rogers, 1994 Jul 18
  - Pages from notebook detailing financial/business obligations of James Gamble Rogers, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agreement between James Gamble Rogers and the firm of Rogers and Butler assigning the business of the former to the latter, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Francis Day Rogers re: stone used by James Gamble Rogers in Woodlawn mausoleum, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)